<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.nasa.gov/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
	<channel>
		<title>NASA Image of the Day</title>
		<description>The latest NASA &quot;Image of the Day&quot; image.</description>
		<link>http://www.nasa.gov/</link>
		<atom:link rel="self"
			href="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss" />
		<language>en-us</language>
		<managingEditor>yvette.smith-1@nasa.gov</managingEditor>
		<webMaster>brian.dunbar@nasa.gov</webMaster>
		<docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
		<item>
			<title>Hubble Peers at the Heart of NGC 5793</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/goddard/hubble-peers-at-the-heart-of-ngc-5793</link>
			<description>This new Hubble image is centered on NGC 5793, a spiral
				galaxy over 150 million light-years away in the constellation of
				Libra. This galaxy has two particularly striking features: a
				beautiful dust lane and an intensely bright center — much brighter
				than that of our own galaxy, or indeed those of most spiral galaxies
				we observe.
				NGC 5793 is a Seyfert galaxy. These galaxies have incredibly luminous
				centers that are thought to be caused by hungry supermassive black
				holes — black holes that can be billions of times the size of the
				sun — that pull in and devour gas and dust from their surroundings.
				This galaxy is of great interest to astronomers for many reasons.
				For one, it appears to house objects known as masers. Whereas lasers
				emit visible light, masers emit microwave radiation. The term
				&quot;masers&quot; comes from the acronym Microwave Amplification by
				Stimulated Emission of Radiation. Maser emission is caused by
				particles that absorb energy from their surroundings and then
				re-emit this in the microwave part of the spectrum.
				Naturally occurring masers, like those observed in NGC 5793, can tell us a
				lot about their environment; we see these kinds of masers in areas
				where stars are forming. In NGC 5793 there are also intense
				mega-masers, which are thousands of times more luminous than the
				sun.
				 
				Credit:  NASA, ESA, and E. Perlman (Florida Institute of Technology)</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/potw1411a.jpg?itok=D6BxQxTu"
				length="112985" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/goddard/hubble-peers-at-the-heart-of-ngc-5793</guid>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Coastal Flooding in New Zealand, Early March</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/coastal-flooding-in-new-zealand-early-march</link>
			<description>A powerful storm passed over New Zealand’s South Island
				in March 2014 and brought gale-force winds, torrential rains, and
				flooding to the city of Christchurch. A total of 74 millimeters (3
				inches) of rain fell on March 4-5, according to MetService, New
				Zealand’s national meteorological service. More than 100 homes
				flooded and more than 4,000 lost power around the country’s third
				most populous city. Skies had cleared enough by March 6, 2014, for
				the Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MODIS) on NASA’s
				Aqua satellite to acquire this image showing the aftermath.
				Coastal communities are becoming increasingly vulnerable to the risk of
				damage and danger from flooding. NASA and NOAA are together
				launching a new opportunity for citizens to work with us on the very
				important topic of coastal flooding. This coastal flooding challenge
				is part of NASA’s third International Space Apps Challenge - a
				two-day global mass collaboration event on April 12-13, 2014. During
				these two days, citizens around the world are invited to engage
				directly with NASA to develop awe-inspiring software, hardware, and
				data visualizations. Last year’s event involved more than 9,000
				global participants in 83 locations. This year will introduce more
				than 60 robust challenges clustered in five themes: asteroids, Earth
				watch, human spaceflight, robotics, and space technology. The
				Coastal Inundation In Your Community challenge is one of four
				climate-related challenges using data provided by NASA, NOAA and
				EPA.
				&gt; 2014 International Space Apps Challenge: Coastal Inundation in Your
				Community
				&gt; NASA Invites Citizens to Collaborate on Coastal Flooding Challenge
				Image Credit: NASA - Jeff Schmaltz, LANCE/EOSDIS MODIS Rapid
				Response Team at NASA GSFC</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/newzealand_amo_2014065_lrg.jpg?itok=63sutqS-"
				length="843155" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/coastal-flooding-in-new-zealand-early-march</guid>
			<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Jupiter&#039;s Great Red Spot Viewed by Voyager I</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/jupiters-great-red-spot-viewed-by-voyager-i</link>
			<description>At about 89,000 miles in diameter, Jupiter could swallow
				1,000 Earths. It is the largest planet in the solar system and
				perhaps the most majestic. Vibrant bands of clouds carried by winds
				that can exceed 400 mph continuously circle the planet&#039;s
				atmosphere. Such winds sustain spinning anticyclones like the Great
				Red Spot -- a raging storm three and a half times the size of Earth
				located in Jupiter’s southern hemisphere. In January and February
				1979, NASA&#039;s Voyager 1 spacecraft zoomed toward Jupiter,
				capturing hundreds of images during its approach, including this
				close-up of swirling clouds around Jupiter&#039;s Great Red Spot.
				This image was assembled from three black and white negatives. The
				observations revealed many unique features of the planet that are
				still being explored to this day.
				&gt; View more images and watch a time-lapse of Jupiter assembled from
				images taken by the spacecraft
				Credit: NASA&#039;s Goddard Space Flight Center. Video and images courtesy
				of NASA/JPL</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/p50142.jpg?itok=LSkKKupA"
				length="8580019" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/jupiters-great-red-spot-viewed-by-voyager-i</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>NASA Releases First Interactive Mosaic of Lunar North Pole</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/nasa-releases-first-interactive-mosaic-of-lunar-north-pole</link>
			<description>Scientists, using cameras aboard NASA&#039;s Lunar
				Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO), have created the largest high
				resolution mosaic of our moon’s north polar region. The
				six-and-a-half feet (two-meters)-per-pixel images cover an area
				equal to more than one-quarter of the United States.
				The images making up the mosaic were taken by the two LRO Narrow Angle
				Cameras, which are part of the instrument suite known as the Lunar
				Reconnaissance Orbiter Camera (LROC). The cameras can record a
				tremendous dynamic range of lit and shadowed areas.
				Web viewers can zoom in and out, and pan around an area. Constructed
				from 10,581 pictures, the mosaic provides enough detail to see
				textures and subtle shading of the lunar terrain. Consistent
				lighting throughout the images makes it easy to compare different
				regions.
				To view the image with zoom and pan capability, visit:
				http://lroc.sese.asu.edu/gigapan.
				Image Credit: NASA/GSFC/Arizona State University</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/gigapan_small_str01.png?itok=O2QgckFt"
				length="3312022" type="image/png" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/nasa-releases-first-interactive-mosaic-of-lunar-north-pole</guid>
			<pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hubble Celebrates 24th Anniversary with Infrared Image of
				Nearby Star Factory</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/hubble-celebrates-24th-anniversary-with-image-of-nearby-star-factory</link>
			<description>In celebration of the 24th anniversary of the launch of
				NASA&#039;s Hubble Space Telescope, astronomers have captured
				infrared-light images of a churning region of star birth 6,400
				light-years away.
				This colorful Hubble Space Telescope mosaic of a small portion of the
				Monkey Head Nebula unveils a collection of carved knots of gas and
				dust silhouetted against glowing gas. The cloud is sculpted by
				ultraviolet light eating into the cool hydrogen gas.
				&gt; Read more
				Image Credit: NASA, ESA, and the Hubble Heritage Team (STScI/AURA)</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/heic1406a.jpg?itok=RDPGvFXB"
				length="1237651" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/hubble-celebrates-24th-anniversary-with-image-of-nearby-star-factory</guid>
			<pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cassini Spacecraft Uses &quot;Pi Transfer&quot; to Navigate
				Path Around Saturn</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/cassini-spacecraft-uses-pi-transfer-to-navigate-path-around-saturn</link>
			<description>On Jan. 19, 2007, the Cassini spacecraft took this view
				of Saturn and its rings -- the visible documentation of a technique
				called a &quot;pi transfer&quot; completed with a Titan flyby. A pi
				transfer uses the gravity of Saturn&#039;s largest moon, Titan, to
				alter the orbit of the Cassini spacecraft so it can gain different
				perspectives on Saturn and achieve a wide variety of science
				objectives. During a pi transfer, Cassini flies by Titan at opposite
				sides of its orbit about Saturn (i.e., Titan&#039;s orbital position
				differs by pi radians between the two flybys) and uses Titan&#039;s
				gravity to change its orbital perspective on the ringed planet.
				&gt; Read more: 5 Ways NASA Uses Pi
				Taking in the rings in their entirety was the focus of this particular
				imaging sequence. Therefore, the camera exposure times were just
				right to capture the dark-side of its rings, but longer than that
				required to properly expose the globe of sunlit Saturn.
				Consequently, the sunlit half of the planet is overexposed.
				The view is a mosaic of 36 images -- that is, 12 separate sets of red,
				green and blue images -- taken over the course of about 2.5 hours,
				as Cassini scanned across the entire main ring system. This view
				looks toward the unlit side of the rings from about 40 degrees above
				the ring plane.
				The images in this natural-color view were obtained with the Cassini
				spacecraft wide-angle camera at a distance of approximately 1.23
				million kilometers (764,000 miles) from Saturn. Image scale is 70
				kilometers (44 miles) per pixel.
				&gt; Read more: Blinding Saturn
				Image Credit: NASA/JPL/Space Science Institute</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/pia08362.jpg?itok=rkLJvzwW"
				length="670967" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/cassini-spacecraft-uses-pi-transfer-to-navigate-path-around-saturn</guid>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Space Communications Antenna Supported Early NASA Missions</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/space-communications-antenna-supported-early-nasa-missions</link>
			<description>This 26 meter (85 foot) antenna operated in Woomera
				(Island Lagoon), Australia at Deep Space Station (DSS) 41,
				established in August 1960. The Island Lagoon site was the first
				deep space station to be established outside the United States and
				the first Australian antenna NASA built. The station was operated by
				the Australian Department of Supply and helped support the Ranger
				and early Mariner missions, as well as communications from the Deep
				Space Network (DSN) complex in Goldstone, California via a moon
				bounce. Woomera’s antenna ceased operations in 1972.
				Today, the Deep Space Network -- consisting of three sites in Goldstone,
				California; Madrid, Spain; and Canberra, Australia -- supports space
				communications for NASA and non-NASA missions that explore the
				furthest points of our solar system. Each complex currently has a 70
				meter (230 foot) antenna, one 34 meter (111 foot) High Efficiency
				(HEF) antenna, and one or more 34 meter Beam Wave Guide (BWG)
				antenna. The Deep Space Network is operated 24 hours a day, seven
				days a week, 365 days per year. To support future mission needs,
				construction is currently underway in Canberra, Australia to add two
				new 34 meter BWG antennas, Deep Space Station 35 (DSS-35) and DSS-36
				by 2018.
				&gt; Read more
				Image Credit: NASA</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/s_band_config_woomera_0.jpg?itok=-cTp5uDl"
				length="2015254" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/space-communications-antenna-supported-early-nasa-missions</guid>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Boosters for Orion Spacecraft&#039;s First Flight Test Arrive
				at Port Canaveral, Florida</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/boosters-for-orion-spacecrafts-first-flight-test-arrive-at-port-canaveral-florida</link>
			<description>A barge arrives at the U.S. Army Outpost wharf at Port
				Canaveral in Florida, carrying two of the three United Launch
				Alliance Delta IV heavy boosters for NASA’s upcoming Exploration
				Flight Test-1 (EFT-1) with the Orion spacecraft. The core booster
				and starboard booster will be offloaded and then transported to the
				Horizontal Integration Facility, or HIF, at Space Launch Complex 37
				on Cape Canaveral Air Force Station. The port booster and the upper
				stage are planned to be shipped to Cape Canaveral in April. At the
				HIF, all three boosters will be processed and checked out before
				being moved to the nearby launch pad and hoisted into position.
				Orion is the exploration spacecraft designed to carry astronauts to
				destinations in deep space, including an asteroid and Mars. It will
				have emergency abort capability, sustain the crew during space
				travel and provide safe re-entry from deep space return velocities.
				During the uncrewed EFT-1 flight, Orion will travel 3,600 miles into
				space -- farther than a spacecraft built for humans has been in more
				than 40 years -- and orbit the Earth twice. The capsule will
				re-enter Earth’s atmosphere at speeds approaching 20,000 mph,
				generating temperatures as high as 4,000 degrees Fahrenheit, before
				splashing down in the Pacific Ocean. The data gathered during the
				flight will influence design decisions, validate existing computer
				models and innovative new approaches to space systems development,
				as well as reduce overall mission risks and costs for later Orion
				flights.
				&gt; Read more
				Image Credit: NASA</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/13090771093_74e7db57f1_o.jpg?itok=pt_FGQro"
				length="4105548" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/boosters-for-orion-spacecrafts-first-flight-test-arrive-at-port-canaveral-florida</guid>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Unpacking Cargo from Expedition 38 Soyuz Landing</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/content/unpacking-cargo-from-expedition-38-soyuz-landing</link>
			<description>Engineers document cargo as it is unloaded from the
				Soyuz TMA-10M spacecraft after it landed with Expedition 38
				Commander Oleg Kotov of the Russian Federal Space Agency, Roscosmos,
				and Flight Engineers: Mike Hopkins of NASA, and, Sergey Ryazanskiy
				of Roscosmos, near the town of Zhezkazgan, Kazakhstan on Tuesday,
				March 11, 2014. Hopkins, Kotov and Ryazanskiy returned to Earth
				after five and a half months onboard the International Space Station
				where they served as members of the Expedition 37 and 38 crews.
				Image Credit: NASA/Bill Ingalls</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/201403110012hq.jpg?itok=LZMwZEYA"
				length="2718085" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/content/unpacking-cargo-from-expedition-38-soyuz-landing</guid>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Rhea&#039;s Day in the Sun</title>
			<link>http://www.nasa.gov/jpl/cassini/saturn-moon-rhea-pia17155</link>
			<description>A nearly full Rhea shines in the sunlight in this recent
				Cassini image. Rhea (949 miles, or 1,527 kilometers across) is
				Saturn&#039;s second largest moon.
				Lit terrain seen here is on the Saturn-facing hemisphere of Rhea. North
				on Rhea is up and rotated 43 degrees to the left. The image was
				taken in visible light with the Cassini spacecraft narrow-angle
				camera on Sept. 10, 2013.
				The view was obtained at a distance of approximately 990,000 miles (1.6
				million kilometers) from Rhea. Image scale is 6 miles (9 kilometers)
				per pixel.
				The Cassini-Huygens mission is a cooperative project of NASA, the
				European Space Agency and the Italian Space Agency. The Jet
				Propulsion Laboratory, a division of the California Institute of
				Technology in Pasadena, manages the mission for NASA&#039;s Science
				Mission Directorate, Washington, D.C. The Cassini orbiter and its
				two onboard cameras were designed, developed and assembled at JPL.
				The imaging operations center is based at the Space Science
				Institute in Boulder, Colo.
				For more information about the Cassini-Huygens mission, visit
				http://www.nasa.gov/cassini and http://saturn.jpl.nasa.gov. The
				Cassini imaging team homepage is at http://ciclops.org
				Image Credit: NASA/JPL-Caltech/Space Science Institute</description>
			<enclosure
				url="http://www.nasa.gov/sites/default/files/styles/946xvariable_height/public/pia17155_full.jpg?itok=AE6f4Hal"
				length="16571" type="image/jpeg" />
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.nasa.gov/jpl/cassini/saturn-moon-rhea-pia17155</guid>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 12:00:00 EDT</pubDate>
			<source url="http://www.nasa.gov/rss/dyn/image_of_the_day.rss">NASA Image of the Day</source>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
